# LEVI MUGALA RESUME

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Address: 9 Prestwick Green, Cranbourne

Phone: 0401 334 493

Email: mugalalevi21@gmail.com

# **CAREER SUMMARY**

I have gained experience in financial management and accounting, having practised at various capacities, recently as a financial accountant at Kenya Agricultural and Livestock Research Institute (KALRO). I have also worked at Kytabu Company Ltd and previously on short internship programs at Kenya Agricultural & Livestock Research Organization (KALRO) and The Capital Markets Authority. As outlined below, I have an understanding and accumulated knowledge in financial management and accounting gained through training on the relevant courses at various tertiary institutions as well as through my personal study time. I have developed self-drive, competence and become a results-oriented professional in this sector, attributes that I keep working on throughout my engagements.

#### **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

# **Masters of Professional Accounting**

HOLMESGLEN INSTITUTE (current)

Skills being developed include:

- Preparation of periodic financial reports in the Australian context.
- Understanding of the business and tax laws
- Preparation of tax invoices
- Critical thinking in business settings.

# **Bachelor of Business Commerce, Finance Option.**

THE UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI, 2012-2016

Nairobi, Kenya.

Introduction to the business environment, emphasis in finance.

### Certified Public Accountant Completed Section 1 and 2.

STRATHMORE UNIVERSITY, 2015 - 2016

Nairobi, Kenya.

Skills developed include bookkeeping, entrepreneurship, cost accounting and financial reporting.

#### **Technical Skills**

Strong: Microsoft Office: Microsoft Word, Excel and PowerPoint.

**Experienced:** Microsoft Access (Database), QuickBooks and Sage-Pastel

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

KENYA AGRICULTURAL AND LIVESTOCK RESEARCH ORGANIZATION. (KALRO) Nairobi-Kenya

One Year Internship Program
July 2018 to June 2019

**Duties & Responsibilities** 

- Ensuring that the imprest form is duly filled and signed by all signatories.
- Follow up on surrender of imprest documents and ensure applicants account for requested funds.
- Voucher preparation.
- Monthly reconciliation of creditors and debtors accounts.
- Keeping track of all purchase orders that have been placed for inventory.
- Filing of documents for future references.
- Develop annual and monthly operating budgets and monthly financial reports.
- Preparation of expense reports, record and reconcile all payments and receipts.

# KYTABU COMPANY LIMITED Nairobi-Kenya Office Admin / Accountant January 2016 to June 2018 Duties & Responsibilities

- Preparing Weekly Reports Reports detailing how petty cash is being managed.
- Planning and Budgeting Assisting in preparing quarterly budgets.
- Payment Vouchers Ensuring that the payment process is duly followed.
- Identifying performance improvement opportunities example, implementing the online accounting system of the organization.
- Interacting with management and shareholders Ensuring that the information flow about the company's financials to the stakeholders is efficient.
- Corresponding with creditors Facilitating receipt of payments due to the company in good time and maintaining a healthy cash reserve.
- Daily Cash Position Daily bank reconciliations on Payments made and Cash received, comparing the company's bank statement.
- Filing Ensuring that all accounting documents are organized.

#### **CAPITAL MARKETS AUTHORITY**

Nairobi-Kenya Intern Finance/Accounts August 2015 – December 2015 Duties & Responsibilities

- Maintaining Daily Cash Position.
- Follow up on outstanding Trade Debtors.
- Receipting, Banking and Posting of receipts.
- Payment Processing-Raising of Payment Vouchers.
- Creditors and Account reconciliations.
- Filing Ensuring that vouchers and other accounting documents are well filled.
- Updating the Cheque Register and dispatching of cheques.

# KENYA AGRICULTURAL AND LIVESTOCK RESEARCH ORGANIZATION. (KALRO) Nairobi-Kenya University Work Placement October 2014 – December 2014 Duties & Responsibilities

- Handling of cash and cheque payments.
- Reconciliation of creditor and debtors accounts monthly.
- Keeps track of all purchase orders that have been placed for inventory.
- Receiving payments from other departments making sure that all supporting documents are attached.
- Develop annual and monthly operating budgets and monthly financial reports.
- Preparation of expense reports, record and reconcile all payments and receipts.

#### **HOPE VENTURES**

Nairobi-Kenya Accounts Assistant June 2011 –August 2012 Duties & Responsibilities

- Handling cash payments and cheque purchases.
- Maintaining cash books.
- Bank reconciliation reconciling the cash books and the bank statement.
- Daily monitoring of the financial transactions for Hope Ventures.
- Cash flow projection and advising management on the financial position of the organization.
- Develop annual and monthly operating budgets.
- Assisting in carrying out quality internal audit and other assurance services on behalf of senior auditors.
- Identifying and communicating accounting and auditing matters to senior managers and partners.

# **Key Employable Skills**

I am well endowed with key employable skills developed over the years through training and professional practice which includes but not limited to the following:-

- Financial Accounting Skills.
- Experienced in administrative duties.
- Computing Skills.
- ExceptioGood Team Player.
- Excellent Leadership and Communication Skills.
- Problem Solving & Customer Experience.
- Ability to break down problems analytically and critically.

# References

Mr Tom Agesa

Warehouse Inventory Controller

CTI Logistics Melbourne, Australia

Phone: 04 2121 5207

Email: tomagesa@gmail.com

Dr Vashanthi M Peter, FIPA FFA CMA BA MA MPhil PhD

Course Leader for Master of Professional Accounting

Holmesglen Institute of TAFE (Chadstone)

Phone: 03 8199 6616

Email: Vasanthi.Peter@holmesglen.edu.au